<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Digital Parenting</string>
    <string name="welcome"><b>welcome to Digital parenting.</b>
        <br>We all know how difficult it can be to source for accurate, summarised and up to date information on how to nurture our little ones. </br>
        <br>
        Digital Parenting App is here to help!
        </br>
        <br>
        Here, you will get all the information regarding the proper ways to take care of your baby,
        </br>
        <br>
        what tools and techniques to use,
        </br>
        <br>
        common myths and misconceptions in our society <b> And so much more!</b>
        </br>
        <br>
        Select the age of your baby below to get information tailored  specifically for his/her age group.
        </br>
        <br>
        And remember, you can always come back to this page to see other information in the other age groups, to prep you for the future!
        </br>

    </string>

    <string name="pregnancy">

</string>

    <string name="six">New mom in town, congrats!
        <br> The first year of the baby’s life is the most essential and vital period of its life; it highly determines the future and outcome of its development by being the first brick of the process. A healthy and well-abled child can indicate proper child care and nurturing,
            and in the opposite case, can indicate negligence and disordered raising.</br>
        <br>
             Having reached the sixth month, the baby is about to progress further into the second half of its first
            year with the aid of a number of skills acquired successfully by that time. There are certain milestones
            that the baby should have reached by the sixth month. These skills vary between intellectual, mental,
            physical, and social, and deserve to have a brief, but clarifying mention in the next few lines.
        </br>
        <br>As your little one approaches the six-months milestone, here is what you should look out for or will start to notice a few things: </br>
    <br> 1. Sleep for fewer hours - The newborn is estimated to have a daily sleep time of eighteen hours at maximum scale. As it grows in age, sleep duration starts to gradually decrease. The baby at six months old is frequently expected to sleep through the night for approximately
        six to eight hours and nap for 1 to 2 hours during the day  </br>
        <br> 2. Babbling and vocalization - Speech skills start to take part in the process of the baby’s development, by the sixth month. The first step including babbling and pronouncing simple prefixes and vowels such as “ma”, “ba” and “ga.” These vocals give rise to clear words with practice and time.
        Some babies are already able to pronounce some easy words at the age of six months, indicating intelligence of a somewhat higher level, as well as focused attention and training by the parents. One of the common ways that is often used to help baby make words is through linking them
            to animal sounds and linking a picture of the animal to the sound</br>
        <br> 3. Rolling over and crawling - (some later than others) Babies frequently roll on their tummies, and many of them are feeling alright with a such position, even during sleeping, other babies may feel distressed. The fact that the baby can roll over makes it a must for the mum to keep an eye on it
            when placed onto the bed or a high place on purpose, for example, diaper changing.</br>
        <br> Crawling is considered a preliminary stage of the baby’s mobility,
            which prepares its body for more developed skills. The mum can use this skill to teach and help her baby use other skills, for example grabbing a toy or reaching the sofa. </br>
        <br> 4. Recognize people, details, objects, words, etc - The cognitive abilities and memory centers of the brain start to exceed being primitive, enabling the baby to remember and recall certain events and people,
            and react to encountering them according to the situation and the people themselves.</br>
        <br>It also stimulate its ability to analyze the surroundings that have an attractive appearance. The baby can be seen during this
            period to focus on special details of some objects, for example flowers or colorful patterns on the mum’s blouse.</br>
        <br> 5. Sitting - By this age, the baby will developed stable control of its head, which will continue developing with further growth.
            The spine also contributes to enabling the baby to sit, even if with support at the beginning. This support can be achieved by the mother’s body,
            the sofa, pillows, stuffed big toys, or any other objects that ensure no harm or discomfort to the baby’s back and head.</br>
        <br> 6. Attention seeking - Previously, crying was used instead of words to express the feelings of hunger, drowsiness, illness, thirst, pain, discomfort due to a dirty diaper, and so forth.
            Crying has been the only way the baby has had to bring attention to their needs. However, at this age the baby
            may cry simply to get attention of the people around her. </br>
        <br> It is important to emphasize the need to develop the child’s self-confidence, therein comes the duty of the parents to stimulate it by caring, and not ignoring.</br>
        <br> 7. Feeding developments - The baby is expected to show interest in several food types that are easy to chew and swallow,
            even if teeth haven’t already started to rise. Of course, the baby is not giving up on breastfeeding or formula just yet, but she should be starting to receive soft foods.
            Cereal is usually the first food introduced, followed by pureed fruits and vegetables. </br>

        <br> https://www.babygaga.com/15-things-the-baby-should-be-able-to-do-at-6-months-old/</br>
    <br>
        ...
    </br>

    </string>

    <string name="half_year">We are counting days to birthday 1.
        <br>Within 12 months, your baby has transformed from a completely helpless newborn into an independent little person.</br>
    <br>
        <b>The journey to one year, baby Milestones:</b>
    </br>
    <br>
        1. Growth  - Your baby’s weight has likely tripled since birth. At month 12, babies also have grown by 50% -- about 9 to 11 inches
        -- and their brain is about 60% of its adult size.
            </br>
        <br>
        2. Motor skills - our 1-year-old should be standing alone and “cruising”-- walking while
            holding onto furniture. They may even have taken those first tentative solo steps.
            </br>
        <br>
        3.Sleep - By one year, your baby should be sleeping less during the day and more at night. Most children at this age still need an afternoon nap,
            but their morning nap may be a thing of the past or the naps may have fused into a longer one in the middle of the day
            </br>
        <br>
        4.Eating - If you’ve been breastfeeding, you might decide that one year is the time to start weaning your baby. It tends to be easier on both mother
            and baby to wean gradually, dropping one feeding at a time. The bedtime feeding is usually the last one to go. To replace nursing, you can give
            your 1-year-old a cup of milk, a snack, or something to suck on.
            </br>
        <br>
           5. Communication - Your baby’s vocabulary is expanding quickly. You’ll probably hear a few words, like “Mama,” “Dada,” “no,” or “uh-oh” on a
            regular basis now. One-year-olds learn language by imitating their parents’ speech, so expect that your baby will turn into a little mimic, if they haven’t done so already.
        </br>
        <br>
            <b>Quick Tips for that child approaching 1 year</b>
        </br>
        <br>
         They love to explore. Provide plenty of opportunities for safe exploration by filling cabinets with unbreakable Tupperware containers,
            wooden spoons, and whisks or by putting large, different textured items inside a box.
        </br>
        <br>
           If your child is a good climber, think about dropping the crib mattress now so that they don’t get a leg-up and fall over the top of the crib railing
        </br>
        <br>
        At your one-year visit, check with your pediatrician to make sure your baby is up-to-date on all vaccinations.
        </br>
        <br>
         Make sure that the house is still baby proofed with stairways gated, no blind cords hanging down where baby can reach them, pots and dishes put back away from counter edges, and household cleaners out of reach.
        </br>
        <br>
         Make sure your baby is in a rear-facing car seat.
        </br>
        <br>https://www.webmd.com/parenting/baby/baby-development-1-year-old</br>
    </string>

    <string name="year">In between age 1 and 2
    <br>During the second year, toddlers are moving around more, and are aware of themselves and their surroundings. Their desire to explore new objects and people also is increasing. </br>
    <br>
       During this stage, toddlers will show greater independence; begin to show defiant behavior; recognize themselves in pictures or a mirror; and imitate the behavior of others, especially adults and older children.
    </br>
    <br>
       Toddlers also should be able to recognize the names of familiar people and objects, form simple phrases and sentences, and follow simple instructions and directions.
    </br>
    <br>
        <b>Positive Parenting Tips</b>
    </br>
        <br>
       1. Read to your toddler daily.
    </br>
        <br>
        2. Ask her to find objects for you or name body parts and objects.
    </br>
        <br>
       3. Play matching games with your toddler, like shape sorting and simple puzzles.
    </br>
        <br>
       4. Encourage him to explore and try new things.
    </br>
        <br>
       5. Help to develop your toddler’s language by talking with her and adding to words she starts.
            For example, if your toddler says “baba”, you can respond, “Yes, you are right―that is a bottle.”
    </br>
        <br>
       6. Encourage your child’s growing independence by letting him help with dressing himself and feeding himself.
    </br>
        <br>
        7. Respond to wanted behaviors more than you punish unwanted behaviors (use only very brief time outs).
            Always tell or show your child what she should do instead.
    </br>
        <br>
        8. Encourage your toddler’s curiosity and ability to recognize common objects by taking field trips together to the park or going on a bus ride.
    </br>
        <br>
       <b> Child Safety First</b>
    </br>
        <br>
        Because your child is moving around more, he will come across more dangers as well. Dangerous situations can
            happen quickly, so keep a close eye on your child. Here are a few tips to help keep your growing toddler safe:
    </br>
        <br>
        1. Do NOT leave your toddler near or around water (for example, bathtubs, pools, ponds, lakes, whirlpools, or the ocean) without someone watching her.
    </br>
        <br>
        2. Block off stairs with a small gate or fence. Lock doors to dangerous places such as the garage or basement.
    </br>
        <br>
        3. Ensure that your home is toddler proof by placing plug covers on all unused electrical outlets.
    </br>
        <br>
        4. Keep sharp objects such as scissors, knives, and pens in a safe place.
    </br>
        <br>
        5. Lock up medicines, household cleaners, and poisons.
    </br>
        <br>
https://www.cdc.gov/ncbddd/childdevelopment/positiveparenting/toddlers.html
    </br>






    </string>

    <string name="twoyears">There are many things you can do to help build a safe, stable,
        and nurturing relationship with your child. These Essentials for Parenting will help you handle some common parenting challenges, so you can be a more confident parent and enjoy helping your child grow.
        <br><b>Quick Tips</b> </br>
    <br>
       1. Communicating with Your Child - praise, learn positive imitation, and active listening to create a good bond.
    </br>
    <br>
        2. Creating Structure and Rules -
Set expectations using family rules, reward charts, and daily schedules.
    </br>
        3. Giving Directions -
Encourage your child to listen by giving simple, effective directions.
        <br>
        4. Using Consequences -
Learn about consequences like ignoring and distraction and tips for discipline.
        </br>
        <br>
        5. Using Time-Out -
Discover tips about when, where, and how to use time out.
        </br>
        <br>
            <b>Healthy Bodies</b>
        </br>
        <br>
        1. Give your child water and plain milk instead of sugary drinks.
        </br>
        <br>
        2. Your toddler might become a very picky and erratic eater. Toddlers need less food because they don’t grow as fast.
            It’s best not to battle with him over this. Offer a selection of healthy foods and let him choose what she wants.
        </br>
        <br>
        3. Limit screen time and develop a media use plan for your family.external icon For children younger than 18 months of age,
            the AAP recommends that it’s best if toddlers not use any screen media other than video chatting.
        </br>
        <br>
        4. Your toddler will seem to be moving continually—running, kicking, climbing, or jumping. Let him be active—he’s developing his coordination and becoming strong.
        </br>
        <br>
https://www.cdc.gov/ncbddd/childdevelopment/positiveparenting/toddlers.html
        </br>

    </string>

    <string name="myths">Myths About Child Development
    <br>that are very untrue: </br>
    <br>
        1. play is frivolous and doesn’t matter
    </br>
    <br>
        2. Do get a flu shot when pregnant-
        Pregnant women can and should get a flu vaccine as long as you don’t have a contraindication as noted by the manufacturer.
    </br>
    <br>
       3. Spanking is an effective form of discipline
    </br>
    <br>
       4. Attachment theory and attachment parenting are the same
    </br>
    <br>
        5. you can spoil a baby by holding them too much (another one I can’t stand to write)
    </br>
    <br>
        6. fussy, high-needs babies turn out to be difficult children (another one that makes me sad)
    </br>
    <br>
        7. Couples dealing with infertility are more likely to get pregnant if they adopt
    </br>
    <br>
        8.  Parents can predict the sex of a fetus by examining the shape of the mother’s body
    </br>
    <br>
        9. The attachment parenting approach strengthens the mother–infant bond
    </br>
        <br>
        10. A woman who is already pregnant can’t get pregnant again
    </br>
        <br>
        11. Epidurals create a high risk of harm during delivery
    </br>
        <br>
        12. Pre-chewing a baby’s food has no known risks
    </br>
        <br>
        13. Bed-wetting is a sign of serious emotional problems
    </br>
        <br>
         14. Vaccines caused the rise in autism diagnoses
    </br>
        <br>
        15. Showing cognitively stimulating videos to babies boosts their intelligence
    </br>
        <br>
        16. Parents can usually tell when their child is depressed
    </br>
    <br>
        17. An “only child” is likely to be selfish, spoiled, and socially incompetent
    </br>
    <br>
https://www.wiley.com/en-us/Great+Myths+of+Child+Development-p-9781118521236
    </br>
    <br>
https://thoughtfulparent.com/child-development-myths
    </br>
    </string>

</resources>